# IAN GABRIEL DURIAN

## IT / WEB DEVELOPER

Blk 16 Lot 35 Brgy Delas Alas GMA Cavite | iangabrieldurian@gmail.com | +639914854229 https://iangabriel09.github.io/My-Portfolio-Updated/



#### **SUMMARY**

I am a highly motivated programmer with experience in web development, technical support, and networking. In my first role, I gained practical skills in building and maintaining websites, as well as troubleshooting and providing support. I also assisted in managing network infrastructure, ensuring smooth system performance and connectivity. I enjoy problem-solving and collaborating with teams to improve both user experiences and IT systems.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Web Development Accessibility IT Troubleshooting
Back-end Web Development Responsive Design IT Networking
Full-stack Web Development User Testing Tools Programming

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Kou Fu Color Printing Corporation**

Jul 2024 - Present

- Spearheaded the creation of dynamic, responsive, and interactive company websites using HTML,
   CSS, JavaScript w/ Jquery, and basic server-side scripting (e.g., PHP).
- Developed and maintained company websites to optimal user experience.
- Researched and studied usable web frameworks such as Laravel in determining the most suitable method of back-end server side scripting within existing websites.
- Improved existing websites by optimizing code, enhancing user experience, and implementing security measures by practicing SQL prepared statements via PHP.
- Provided technical support, troubleshooting hardware, software, and network-related issues, ensuring minimal downtime and maximum productivity.
- Managed local area network (LAN) infrastructure, including router and switch configuration, IP addressing, and network diagnostics to ensure optimal performance and connectivity.
- Documented troubleshooting steps, resolutions, and system configurations for future reference and knowledge sharing.

#### Highly Succeed Inc. | Intern as Database Programmer

Aug 2022 - Oct 2022

- Assist with Database Maintenance
- Basic Query Writing
- Contributed to creating and updating documentation related to database configurations, procedures, and troubleshooting steps.
- Database Backups: participated in database backup procedures and data recovery processes.
- Data Entry and Verification: Input and validate data in the database to ensure accuracy and integrity.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Aug 2019 - Apr 2024

Cavite State University Main Campus

# **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- Languages: English, Filipino.
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, PHP, SQL.
- Web Frameworks: Laravel, Bootstrap, Tailwind.
- Additional Programming languages: Python, Java, C#.
- Certifications: Udemy: Full Stack Web Development From Zero with PHP 2022.